Kontakt

www.linkedin.com/in/janine-lechermann-a8618776 (LinkedIn)

Top-Kenntnisse

Business Development Pressearbeit Produktmarketing

Languages

Deutsch (Native or Bilingual) Englisch (Full Professional) Französisch (Elementary) Spanisch (Elementary)

Honors-Awards

Student of the Year 2017 #30under30 (PR Report)

Janine Lechermann

Senior Communications Specialist for Leadership Communications bei Siemens | #30u30 by PR Report 2021

München

Zusammenfassung

A highly motivated specialist in the field of Corporate Communications with over ten years of professional experience. I'm keen on taking on new challenges, developing my skills, expanding my network and working in an exciting and inspiring environment.

Berufserfahrung

Siemens

10 Jahre 7 Monate

Senior Communications Specialist for Leadership Communications Mai 2021 - Present (11 Monate)

München, Bayern, Deutschland

- Community building & management for the Siemens leaders community
- •# Event management for leadership events
- Development team for a new leadership narrative
- Member of the Project Management Office for the first virtual Siemens Business Conference
- Communications & workstream lead for an inclusive language guideline at Siemens
- Session owner & internal communications lead for the Siemens Communications Conference 2021
- Moderator of a working group to establish Happier Habits at the workplace

Referent to Global Head of Communications

Januar 2020 - April 2021 (1 Jahr 4 Monate)

München und Umgebung, Deutschland

- Providing support for Head of Comms for strategic and operative tasks
- Development of communications concepts & strategies
- Preparation of presentations, briefings, articles etc. for Head of Comms
- Co-project lead for the first fully virtual Siemens Communications Conference
- Planning of internal events (e.g. Communication Townhalls, Ask Me Anything-sessions)

- Preparation and follow-up of management meetings with regards to content and organization
- Interface to specialist departments on an international level
- Public relations / press support
- Research on strategic topics

Communications Manager

September 2019 - Dezember 2019 (4 Monate)

Berlin und Umgebung, Deutschland

- Channel management around "Siemensstadt 2.0" (Berlin), i.e. social media, website etc.
- Pacesetter for IOT Communications Strategy

Communications Consultant

Mai 2017 - August 2019 (2 Jahre 4 Monate)

Berlin

- Consulting of the East German subsidiaries with regards to PR, employee & customer comms
- Creating concepts for, planning and realizing VIP customer events as well as employee events
- Content production for and curation of the intranet and internet pages of the subsidiaries
- Content management of internal platforms such as Yammer and the Siemens NewsCenter
- Planning and realization of PR activities as well as sponsoring activities and donations
- Project management and controlling (order placements, invoice processing, budget management)
- Consulting of the entities with regards to Corporate Design / brand topics

Project Assistant / Market Communications

Juli 2015 - April 2017 (1 Jahr 10 Monate)

München und Umgebung, Deutschland

Among other things, support and project coordination of the global Siemens brand re-launch.

Advisor / Press department Oktober 2014 - Juli 2015 (10 Monate)

Assistant to Deputy Head of Communications

Juli 2013 - Oktober 2014 (1 Jahr 4 Monate)

München und Umgebung, Deutschland

Apprentice: Management assistant

September 2011 - Juni 2013 (1 Jahr 10 Monate)

Metropolregion München

Kauffrau für Büromanagement (IHK)

Ausbildung

AKAD University

Master of Arts - MA, Global Management & Communication · (2021 - 2024)

AKAD-University

Bachelor of Arts (BA), International Business Communication · (2013 - 2017)

Siemens AG

Kauffrau für Büromanagement (IHK) · (2011 - 2013)